Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin autograph collection, 1833-2008.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gail and Stephen Rudin autograph collection, 1833-2008.
6875
Rudin, Stephen,
251 items.
Correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
251 letters and other documents recording the achievements of notable artists, politicians, scientists, architects, businessmen and women, journalists, musicians, and educators.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
251 letters and other documents recording the achievements of notable artists, politicians, scientists, architects, businessmen and women, journalists, musicians, and educators.
Additional letters (ca. 107).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rudin, Stephen,
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Anthony, Susan B. Addressee: Mrs. Watson Writer's location: Rochester, New York, August 25, 1882; ALS; Pages: 2 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
  "To get the right to vote secured to the women of this nation!" First Day Covers and Coins are also included in this file.
  Rudin # A-1
- Armstrong, Neil, n.d.; TMsS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  "What America Means To Me".
  Rudin # A-2
- Audubon, John J. Addressee: John Kirk Townsend Writer's location: Charleston, South Carolina, November 4, 1833; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Refers to a possible new bird species and requests research be done as to whether the species is a distinct one or not. Is writing the second volume of the Ornithological Biography. With this lot is the program for the first day of issue ceremony of the 1985 Audubon stamp.
  Rudin # A-3
- Powell, Robert Baden Addressee: C.V. Swan Writer's location: London, January 24, 1919; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Congratulating Swan and his group of Scouts on their work with the Coastwatching Service during the War.
  Rudin # A-4
- Barnum, P.T. Addressee: Robert Collyer Writer's location: Bridgeport, Connecticut, April 26, 1887; ALS - 5.75" x 9"; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Discusses his bout of exhaustion and his resolve to "take it easy".
  Rudin # A-5
- Barnum, P.T. Addressee: Mr. H.P.R. Holt Writer's location: Bridgeport, Connecticut, July 19, 1889; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Offers sage advice for happiness and salvation.
  Rudin # A-6
- Bartholdi, Frederic Auguste Addressee: Cheri Madame Writer's location: New York, August 26, 1876; ALS - 5" x 8"; Pages: 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  The sculptor attempts to raise funds to build the Statue of Liberty. In French, with translation.
  Rudin # A-7
- Bartholdi, Frederic Auguste Writer's location: Paris, 1883; Pamphlet 6.25" x 9.25"; Pages: 36 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Pamphlet entitled "La Statue de la Liberte, Eclairant Le Monde" signed and inscribed by Bartholdi. (36 pages plus two fold-out plates).
  Rudin # A-8
- Bartholdi, Frederic Auguste Writer's location: New York, 1886; Ribbon 2.25" x 6" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  1886 silk souvenir ribbon printed around the time of the dedication of the Statue of Liberty.
  Rudin # A-8A
- Barton, Clara Addressee: Lucy Ellen Guernsey Writer's location: Johnstown, Pennsylvania, September 5, 1889; ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  In the aftermath of the devastating Johnston Flood, Barton gushes "It takes great courage to begin again the struggle for existence".
  Rudin # A-9
- Barton, Clara Addressee: Charles S. Smith Writer's location: Washington, DC, February 1, 1892; TLS - 4to; Pages: 4 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Barton requests assistance for food in the first overseas mission of the Red Cross for The Russian Famine of 1892.
  Rudin # A-10
- Barton, Clara Addressee: Col. S.W. Hill Writer's location: Constantinople, May 21, 1896; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Barton describes relief efforts in Turkey after the Armenian massacres.
  Rudin # A-11
- Barton, Clara Addressee: Mrs. Donald McLean Writer's location: Glen Echo, MD, January 15, 1904; ALS - 5" x 6.5"; Pages: 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  An embattled Barton resists attacks on her conduct as Red Cross President.
  Rudin # A-12
- Beauregard, G.T. - Addressee: Confederate Commissioners Writer's location: Charleston, South Carolina, March 20, 1861; Telegram Not Signed by Beauregard; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  "Sumter not evacuated, Anderson is still working on its defenses". See also letter Claim for Impressed Slave who died while working on Ft. Sumter (S. Carolina), Rudin #151 in collection #4681.
  Rudin # A-13
- Beecher, Henry Ward Addressee: "My dear Sir" Writer's location: n.p., January 9, 1867; ALS - 4" x 5"; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Beecher agrees to marry couple under unusual circumstances - a man wants to marry his deceased wife's sister.
  Rudin # A-14
- Bell, Alexander Graham Addressee: "My dear Senator" (Unnamed) Writer's location: Washington, D.C., January 20, 1900; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Bell urges Census amendment for the hearing impaired.
  Rudin # A-15
- Bell, Alexander Graham Addressee: Charles H. Swan Writer's location: Boston, 1908; Signed Inscribed Book; Pages: 469
  "The Deposition of Alexander G. Bell In The Suit Brought By The United States To Annul the Bell Patents". Book inscribed to Charles H. Swan, Bell's Patent Attorney who also wrote the introduction to the book. See also Selden, Edison, Tesla and Wright for other patents. See separate material below.
  Rudin # A-16
- Bell, Alexander Graham Writer's location: United States Patent Office, March 28, 1922; Printed Patent 7.5" x 11.25"; Pages: 12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Patent for Hydrodome, hydro-aeroplane and the like.
  Rudin # A-17
- Ben Gurion, David Addressee: Zelman Aran Minister of Education Writer's location: n.p., March 11, 1967; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 3 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Discusses the importance of educating the poor in Israel. (In Hebrew, with translation.) Included is a signed title page from his book, "Memoirs", AmOved Publishers, Tel Aviv 1971.
  Rudin # A-18
- Berlin, Irving Addressee: Mrs. Dick Bernie Writer's location: New York, August 10, 1944; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Berlin writes about his army tour playing for the troops.
  Rudin # A-19
- Bernstein, Leonard Writer's location: n.p. (Boston), September 24, 1934; AMsS - 8vo; Pages: 4 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Early essay by Bernstein - "I am filled all the more with the desire for a musical life".
  Rudin # A-20
- Bernstein, Leonard Addressee: Renee Longy-Miquelle Writer's location: New York, NY, August 31, 1945; ALS 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Bernstein writes to his former teacher and extemporizes on his ambitions for transforming American music.
  Rudin # A-21
- Bernstein, Leonard Addressee: Hans Heinsheimer Writer's location: Cuernavaca, Mexico, May 15, 1951; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Bernstein expresses his concerns over Trouble in Tahiti, the Age of Anxiety and his Anniversaries for Piano.
  Rudin # A-22
- Bobbie Skate, 1920's (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Documents, letters and patents pertaining to the Bobbie Skate, a forerunner of the Roller Blade.
  Rudin # M-82
- Borden, Lizzie Writer's location: Fall River, MA, August 4, 1892 - May 30, 1893; Album (Box 8)
  An album containing a large collection of manuscripts, documents and newspaper clippings all pertaining to the murder of Andrew and Abby Borden and the arrest and trial of Lizzie Borden for the murders.
  Rudin # A-22A
- Bridgeman, Laura Addressee: Mr. Brown Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; ALS -; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  One of the first deaf and blind people to be educated. Declines an invitation.
  Rudin # A-23
- Bryan, William Jennings Addressee: Paul Fuller, Jr. Writer's location: En Route to San Francisco, June 28, 1915; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Letter written shortly after he resigned as Secretary of State.
  Rudin # A-24
- Bunche, Ralph Johnson Addressee: Miss. Doris Busby Writer's location: New York, December 3, 1953; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Bunche defines the "basic tenets of the American way of life" for a high school history class.
  Rudin # A-25
- Burbank, Luther Addressee: Katharine L. Ward Writer's location: Santa Rosa, California, January 17, 1921; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Thanks his correspondent for flower and herbal books and comments on his new puppy, "more intelligent in many ways than the average citizen".
  Rudin # A-26
- Burger, Warren Addressee: Walter Bitterling Writer's location: Washington, D.C., July 14, 1981; TLS; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Burger compares John Kennedy to Lyndon Johnson.
  Rudin # A-26A
- Burr, Aaron Addressee: A.B. (Self) Writer's location: New York, February 12, 1829; Signed Check; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Aaron Burr draws check from Manhattan Company for $500 made out to himself.
  Rudin # A-27
- Butler, Nicholas Murray Addressee: Reverand Paul R. Hickok Writer's location: New York City, January 10, 1920; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Butler continues his crusade against the recent implementation of prohibition.
  Rudin # A-28
- Byrd, Richard Addressee: To his wife, Marie Writer's location: Byrd Arctic Expedition S.S. Chantier, May 6, 7, 1926; ALS - 4to; Pages: 7 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  A series of four autograph letters written to his wife shortly before take-off for the North Pole.
  Rudin # A-29
- Byrd, Richard Writer's location: New York, May 10 - 17, 1926; Newspapers (7 items) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Byrd's flight to the North Pole and the Arctic flight of the dirigible "Norge" are covered in seven New York Times issues.
  Rudin # A-30
- Byrd, Richard Writer's location: G.P. Putnam's Sons New York, 1930; Book Signed; Pages: 436
  "Little America: Aerial Exploration in the Antarctic, The Flight to the South Pole". See separated material below.
  Rudin # A-31
- Byrd, Richard Addressee: Mrs. E.R. Newell Writer's location: Boston, MA, October 4, 1933; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Byrd asks a supporter for funds to purchase Eskimo dogs for the 1933-34 Antarctic expedition.
  Rudin # A-32
- Byrd, Richard Writer's location: G.P. Putnam's Sons New York, 1938; Book Signed; Pages: 296
  The book "Alone" describes Byrd's Antarctic expedition. See separated material below.
  Rudin # A-33
- Byrd, Richard, 1933-1980; Stamps (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Stamps and First Day Covers - commemorating Byrd's flights over the South Pole.
  Rudin # A-34
- Carnegie, Andrew Addressee: Mrs. Grover Cleveland Writer's location: New York, May 9, 1908; ALS 4" x 6"; Pages: 4 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Comments on the progress of Cleveland's health and suggests that doctors order him Scotch Whiskey which he has sent.
  Rudin # A-35
- Carnegie, Andrew Addressee: Dr. S. Weir Mitchell Writer's location: New York, November 17, 1909; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Explains reasons for establishing the "Hero Fund".
  Rudin # A-36
- Carver, George Washington Addressee: Bob Barry Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, March 30, 1931; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Letter to peanut company telling them about his research on several peanut diseases.
  Rudin # A-37
- Carver, George Washington Addressee: Henry H Overton Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, September 16, 1931; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Letter sharing the loss of his money during the Depression.
  Rudin # A-38
- Carver, George Washington Addressee: Grady Porter Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, January 21, 1932; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Letter reviewing specimens of fungi.
  Rudin # A-39
- Carver, George Washington Addressee: "My dear boy, Mr. Davis" Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, July 2, 1932; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Discusses carefully balanced meals and "putting of the peanut into the home as a regular part of the daily menu".
  Rudin # A-40
- Carver, George Washington Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, June 1925, February 1943; Two Pamphlets 8vo; Pages: a.14 b.30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  a. "The Peanut". b. "How to Grow the Peanut and 105 Ways of Preparing it for Human Consumption".
  Rudin # A-41
- Catt, Carrie Chapman Addressee: Office of the Secretary Navy Department Writer's location: New York, May 10, 1916; TLS - 5.5" x 9.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Letter asking for endorsement of woman suffrage. A brochure is attached to the letter. Also included is a broadside warning of women's suffrage.
  Rudin # A-42
- Churchill, Winston Addressee: Louis A. Sendel Writer's location: London, S.W. 7, February 8, 1947; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  A thank you note for a box of cigars.
  Rudin # A-43
- Churchill, Winston Addressee: Pamela, Countess of Lytton Writer's location: Chartwell, Westerham, Kent, August 14, 1951; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Churchill writes of his painting, toiling at the book, memories of better times and his thoughts of the position of independent India.
  Rudin # A-44
- Clay, Henry Addressee: John Howard Payne Esq. Writer's location: Washington, n.d.; Envelope 4.5" x 2.75" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Free-franked address panel signed by Clay.
  Rudin # A-45
- Clay, Henry Writer's location: Fayette County Circuit Court, September 17, 1805; ADS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  A legal deposition signed "Clay".
  Rudin # A-46
- Cohan, George M. Addressee: George Bucks Writer's location: n.p., April 5, 1941; ALS - small 4to; Pages: 9 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Cohan's humorous response to the letter writer who requested that he write 700-800 words for an "Anniversary Number".
  Rudin # A-47
- Colt, Samuel Addressee: To the Editor of the New York Tribune Writer's location: Hartford, CT, December 19, 1861; LS 7.5" x 9.75"; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Important Civil War letter written to assure the Editor that his company is dedicated to the Federal Government and not to aiding the rebels in the Southern States.
  Rudin # A-48
- Cosey, Joseph Addressee: Writer's location: Philadelphia, September 10, 1787; ALS; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Cosey forgery of Benjamin Franklin signature.
  Rudin # M-57
- Cosey, Joseph Addressee: Writer's location: Philadelphia, January 8, 1863; ALS; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Cosey forgery of Abraham Lincoln's signature.
  Rudin # A-57A
- Cox, Archibald Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Letter regretting Supreme Court's involvement in the 2000 Presidential election.
  Rudin # A-49
- Cox, Archibald Addressee: Dean Collins Writer's location: Harvard Law School Cambridge, MA, January 25, 1991; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Explains what he thinks Haig's role was in Watergate cover-up.
  Rudin # A-50
- Cox, Archibald Addressee: Mr. S. Liuna ? Writer's location: Brooksville, ME, April 13, 2000; ALS - 6" x 7"; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Gives his opinion regarding the impeachment of President Bill Clinton.
  Rudin # A-51
- Cox, Archibald Addressee: Mr. Hoffert Writer's location: Brooksville, ME, July 11, 2003; TLS - 4to; Pages: 3 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Letter to history teacher answering several questions about Richard Nixon.
  Rudin # A-52
- Cox, Archibald Addressee: Kelly Web Writer's location: Harvard Law School, November 17, 1998; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Response to a question asking if Cox believed President Ford acted wisely in pardoning Nixon.
  Rudin # A-53
- Cox, Archibald Addressee: Alex Oblado Writer's location: Brooksville, ME, March 27, 2003; ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  "Would you not agree that President Nixon's wrongdoing was more dangerous to the country than President Clinton's?"
  Rudin # A-54
- Cox, Archibald, TDS; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 20A)
  As Watergate special prosecutor, Cox states "Even the president must be subject to the law"
  Rudin # A-54A
- Charles, Darrow, December 31, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Monopoly Board Game Patent by Charles B. Darrow.
- Darrow, Clarence Addressee: Dr. Theodore Perceval Gerson Writer's location: Chicago, December 29, 1920; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Personal letter about a Los Angeles trial.
  Rudin # A-55
- Darwin, Charles Addressee: Ferdinand Julius Cohn Writer's location: Down, Beckenham, Kent, August 8, 1877; LS - 8vo; Pages: 4 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Letter to a German botanist discussing recently published observations made by Darwin's son.
  Rudin # A-56
- Davis, Jefferson
  See the Gail and Stephen Rudin Civil War Collection, #4696.
- Deforest, Lee Addressee: Thomas K. Boyce Writer's location: Los Angeles, CA, January 5, 1952; TLS -4to; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Responds to a question about today's television. Accompanied by patent sketch of electrical current amplification device (Actually, a first day of issue of the 11 cent "Progress in Electronic" stamp).
  Rudin # A-61
- Deforest, Lee Addressee: Mr. Olsen Writer's location: Los Angeles, CA, August 18, 1952; ALS & TLS 5.5" x 3.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Father of radio comments on the aid to democracy talking pictures and television can be.
  Rudin # A-62
- Dix, Dorothea Addressee: His Excellency the Governor Writer's location: Raleigh, SC, December 30, 1848; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Writes letter thanking the General Assembly of SC for their vote to pay for the construction of a hospital for the insane.
  Rudin # A-63
- Dix, Dorothea Addressee: Unknown Writer's location: Washington, DC, November 6, 1862; ALS - 8" x 5"; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Dix pleads with recipient not to send nurses who do not appear to be "matronly".
  Rudin # A-64
- Dix, Dorothea Writer's location: Washington, DC, October 29, 1863; Printed DOC 4.5" x 7"; Pages: 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  General Orders 351 - On employment of women nurses during the Civil War.
  Rudin # A-65
- Earhart, Amelia Addressee: Robert James Braly Writer's location: New York City, January 28, 1929; TLS 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Predicts the future of aviation.
  Rudin # A-66
- Earhart, Amelia Addressee: Dr. R.E. Whitehead Writer's location: Rye, New York, September 25, 1934; TLS 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 1a)
  Earhart suggests statistics should be gathered for women pilots "We do not know how they react to altitude, or fatigue, or anything else, as we do men."
  Rudin # A-66A
- Earhart, Amelia Addressee: Miss. Ursula Toomey Writer's location: New York City, March 28, 1930; TLS 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Earhart is pleased that more women are showing an interest in aviation.
  Rudin # A-67
- Earhart, Amelia Addressee: Federal Communications Commission Writer's location: Union Air Terminal Burbank, California, August 8, 1936; Postscript Signed 3" x 8"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Earhart licensing the aircraft for her last flight.
  Rudin # A-68
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: Orange, NJ, ca. 1898; Autograph Draft - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Edison's working draft of a letter relating to foreign royalties on the photograph.
  Rudin # A-69
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; Typed DOC 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 19 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Questions and answers posed to civil engineers and mechanical engineers seeking employment at Edison Laboratories.
  Rudin # A-70
- Edison, Thomas Addressee: Buchanan Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Asks departments to reduce payrolls.
  Rudin # A-71
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: Menlo Park, NJ, December 27, 1881; Printed Patent 7.25" x 10.75"; Pages: 3 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Electric Lamp Patent to provide the lamp with a simpler and cheaper base. See also Selden, Bell, Tesla and Wright for other patents.
  Rudin # A-72
- Edison, Thomas Addressee: Hon. Abram S. Hewitt Writer's location: New York, May 15, 1883; LS 6" x 9.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Edison agrees to light Cooper Institute.
  Rudin # A-73
- Edison, Thomas Addressee: Edwin Elsbach Writer's location: Orange, NJ, October 9, 1918; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Discusses his experiments on ink which could facilitate printing for the blind.
  Rudin # A-74
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: West Orange, NJ, November 16, 1920; T DOC S 7.75" x 11"; Pages: 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Minutes of a meeting of the Board of Directors of Thomas A. Edison, Inc. discussing calculations of costs of various models of phonographs as well as the pricing of a main spring lubricant.
  Rudin # A-75
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: West Orange, NJ, March 8, 1922; T DOC S - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Minutes of a Meeting of the Board of Directors of Phonographs, Limited - Edison elected President of the Corporation.
  Rudin # A-76
- Edison, Thomas Addressee: Buchanan Writer's location: (Orange, NJ), March 24 ca. 1924; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Letter informing that the demand for records will fall off on account of...radio.
  Rudin # A-77
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: West Orange, NJ, August 27, 1924; T DOC S - 4to; Pages: 3 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Minutes of a Special Meeting of the Stockholders of Edison Phonograph Distributing Company to approve the merger with Phonograph Corp. of Indiana.
  Rudin # A-78
- Edison, Thomas Writer's location: n.p., June 10, 1927; Pencil Drawing 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Original pencil electrical circuit drawing. Sound equipment for recording music for phonographs.
  Rudin # A-79
- Edison, Thomas Addressee: W.H. Hand Writer's location: West Orange, NJ, September 21, 1928; Signed Check 3" x 8.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  A misprinted check signed by Thomas Edison.
  Rudin # A-80
- Edison, Thomas Addressee: Edward Cranch Writer's location: Orange, NJ, January 11, 1915; TLS - 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Edison discusses the phonograph and optimistically reports on record production after a fire destroyed his plant.
  Rudin # A-81
- Einstein, Albert Addressee: Robert Friedman Writer's location: Princeton, NJ, June 10, 1969; TLS - 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 1, 1 photo (Box 3, Folder 16a)
  Einstein congratulates the addressee for his work with Jewish refugees. He states, "We have no other means of self defense than our solidarity and our knowledge that the cause for which we are suffering is a momentous and sacred cause."
  Rudin # A-81A
- Ellsworth, Oliver Addressee: John Lawrence, Treasurer Writer's location: Hartford, CT, July 4, 1776; ADS Small 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Revolutionary War document dates 7/4/1776 requesting payment for boarding officers, prisoners of war.
  Rudin # A-82
- Ervin, Sam Addressee: Steven Rubin Writer's location: Morganton, NC, September 13, 1979; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Ervin believes President Ford should not have pardoned Nixon.
  Rudin # A-83
- King Ferdinand and Queen Isabella Writer's location: Medina del Campo, May 6, 1504; DS 8.5" x 12"; Pages: 1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  King and Queen of Spain -- signed manuscript document ordering payment to workers who hadn't been paid.
  Rudin # A-84
- Ford, Henry Addressee: Colonel L.S. Horner Writer's location: Detroit, December 19, 1918; TLS Narrow 4to; Pages: 1 1/3 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Comments on how the Liberty motor (in airplanes) contributed to ending the war.
  Rudin # A-85
- Franklin, Benjamin Writer's location: Philadelphia, March 1, 1787; DS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Notarization of petition of bankruptcy.
  Rudin # A-86
- Franklin, Benjamin Writer's location: Province of Pennsylvania, May 20, 1758; Printed Bank Note 2.5" x 3.25"; Pages: 2 (Box 11)
  Twenty shilling bank note printed by B. Franklin and D. Hall.
  Rudin # A-86A
- Freud, Anna Addressee: Mr. Baker Writer's location: London, August 10, 1944; TLS - 7" x 9"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Letter from Freud's daughter adhering to his wishes to protect his private life.
  Rudin # A-87
- Gandhi, Indira Addressee: Mr. Paul Dennett Writer's location: New Delhi, March 31, 1975; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)